grapevineassociatesinc.com 2009-08-08

# privacystatement

Privacy Policy:

Your personal information will be kept strictly confidential.  I will not share, sell or give your information to anyone or   
for any reason.  The information collected from you will be used solely for the management of this site and your   
membership.

We know that you care how your information is used, and we appreciate your trust that we will use it carefully and   
sensibly. This notice describes our privacy policy. By visiting us, you are accepting the privacy policy described   
below.

1\.  What Personal Information Do We Collect?

Information You Provide.  We receive and store information you enter.  For example, when you search for or buy a   
product or service, or when you supply information such as your address, phone number or credit card. You can   
choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of some of our   
features.  We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, customizing   
future shopping for you, improving our website, and communicating with you.  In addition, if you choose, we may   
share your information with other companies who provide goods or services that you are interested in.  Please see   
the “opt-in/opt-out” selection in Section 4 of this policy.  
Cookies. Like many websites, we use "cookies".  Cookies are small programs that we transfer to your hard drive   
that allow us to recognize you and to provide you with a customized shopping experience.  If you do not want us to   
use cookies, you can easily disable them by going to the toolbar of your web browser, and clicking on the “help”   
button.  Follow the instructions that will prevent the browser from accepting cookies, or set the browser to inform   
you when you receive a new cookie.  In addition, you may visit this and other websites anonymously through the   
use of utilities provided by other private companies.  
Other Information: Every computer has an IP (Internet Protocol) address.  IP addresses of computers used to visit   
this site are noted.  In addition, we automatically collect other information such as email addresses, browser types,   
operating systems, and the URL addresses of sites clicked to and from this site.  
Information from Other Sources.  We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to our   
account information.  This may include updated delivery and address information from our shippers or other   
sources so that we can correct our records and deliver your next purchase or communication more easily.    
2\.  How Do We Use Your Information?

Customized Shopping.  We use your information to better serve you by providing a customized shopping   
experience.  As noted above, you may “opt-out” of this customization, or even visit and shop anonymously.  
Agents. We employ other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include   
delivering packages, sending postal mail and e-mail, and processing credit card payments. They have access to   
personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for other purposes.  
Special Offers.  We may send you special offers from time to time, unless you choose to “opt-out” of receiving such   
offers.  In addition, we may also send you special offers from other companies.  Again, you may “opt-out”.  If we   
send you offers from other businesses, we do not share your personal information with them.  The offers come   
directly through us.  Please see the “opt-in/opt-out” selection at the end of this policy.    
Business Transfers. As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy stores or assets. In such   
transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the unlikely event   
that we are acquired, customer information will be one of the transferred assets.  
Law Enforcement.   If we receive a lawful court order to release account or other personal information then we will   
comply with the law.  We will also release information when necessary to protect the life, safety or property of   
others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and   
credit risk reduction.

3\.  How Do We Protect the Security of Your Information?

We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL)   
software, which encrypts information you input.  
We use encryption to protect your information contained in our customer list.  
We use a firewall to protect against unlawful intrusion.  
We limit access to your information on a “need to know” basis.  
We reveal only the last five digits of your credit card numbers when confirming an order. Of course, we transmit the   
entire credit card number to the appropriate credit card company during order processing.  
It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to   
sign off when finished using a shared computer.  
No system can guarantee absolute security, just as the finest lock can not guarantee physical security.  However,   
we take every reasonable precaution to assure that your data is secure.  
4\.  Your Choice:  Opt-in or Opt-out.

It is your choice whether to receive emails or special offers from us or others.  The following section provides you   
with this choice.  Please note the default settings.

·        Please send me email or other mail informing me of special offers of your products or services.

·        Please do not send me email or other mail informing me of special offers of your products or services.

·        Please send me email or other mail informing me of special offers of related products or services from other   
companies.

·        Please do not send me email or other mail informing me of special offers of related products or services from   
other companies.

5\.  Children

We do not sell products or services to children. If you are under 18, you may use this site only with involvement of   
a parent or guardian.

6\.  Other Websites

Various Web sites may be linked to from this site.  If you link to another site, your privacy depends on the policy of   
that site.  We strongly urge you to check their privacy policy.  Not all sites guarantee that they will not share your   
personally identifiable information with others.  You may also wish to consult privacy guidelines such as those   
recommended by the Online Privacy Alliance (www.privacyalliance.org).

7\.  Contact Us

If you would like to learn more about our privacy policy, or to access your personally identifiable information   
contained on our website, you may contact us at ________.  You will be required to provide identifier information to   
assure that this information is not released to others.  We reserve the right to modify this policy in the future.  If we   
do so, notice will be posted on our home page.

*********************************

NOTES

Section 1.   Different sites will collect different information.  For example, if you do not collect credit card   
information, do not include this.  YOUR site must be customized for the data that you collect.  Same with cookies.  If   
you do not use them, simply state that.  

Section 2.  It is highly recommended that you not sell your customer lists or other personally identifiable information   
to others, e.g. marketing firms or other companies.  It is far better to rent out a one time use of selected customers,   
where YOU send out the email offers of another company.  That way the information never leaves your premises   
and is always under your control.  If however you plan to sell or rent the p.i. information of your customers, you   
should inform them of this possibility and give them an opportunity to opt-out of that action.

Section 3.  You must provide the security you promise.  Different levels of security are appropriate for different   
types of businesses.  You should certainly have a firewall and limited access protection, at a minimum.  Encryption   
of the customer list is highly recommended, and is getting easier.

Section 4.  The opt-in/opt-out section is very important.  The bullets represent clickable choices, that is, circles that   
can be dotted.  You will want to set the default settings on the choices #1 and #3, that allow you to send special   
offers from your own site and also from related companies.

Section 5.  There are special laws protecting the privacy of children, including the federal Childrens’ Online Privacy   
Protection Act (COPPA).  It is safest not to sell to or collect information from children.  If your site is specifically   
directed at children, then you should seek specific legal advice on how to comply with these laws.

Section 6.  Privacy guidelines require that visitors be able to access their information.

MOST IMPORTANT:  DO NOT MAKE YOUR PRIVACY POLICY STRONGER THAN NECESSARY, AND BE SURE   
TO FOLLOW IT.  TAILOR THE POLICY TO YOUR SITE.  SEEK THE ADVISE OF LEGAL COUNSEL THAT IS   
EXPERIENCED IN E-COMMERCE ISSUES.  REMEMBER:  IT IS FAR BETTER TO HAVE NO PRIVACY POLICY   
THAN ONE WHICH IS VIOLATED.
